Gentlemen of the Yamato,
our Chief, Isao Kondo
[Note: Spoof of Space Battleship
Yamato series anime.]
(土方)あ～ あ～ 大和の諸君➡
我らが局長
近藤 勲は無事 救出した！
has been safely rescued.
Victory is within our grasp!
(土方)勝機は 我らの手にあり！
局長の顔に泥を塗り
受けた恩を仇で返す不逞の輩➡
We shall get revenge on
[Note: Spoof of GUNDAM series anime.]
that lawless bunch for besmirching
our Chief's name. Let me say this.
あえて言おう… ｶｽであると！
They are all scum!
In the name of the moon...
[Note: Spoof of Sailor Moon.]
今こそ ﾔﾂらを
月に代わって お仕置きするのだ！
we will punish them!!
[無線](隊士)おい 誰だ!?
気の抜けた演説してるﾔﾂは！
Hey, who's that? Who's making
that silly speech?
Who am I? I'm Shinsengumi
Vice-Chief...
誰だと…!?
真選組副長 土方 十四郎なり！
Toshiro Hijikata nari!!
[Note: Suffix "Nari" was used by Samurai and by
Korosuke in the Kiteretsu Daihyakka anime.]
(新八)土方さん…｡
Hijikata-san...
Mr. Kondo, we shall protect your life.
近藤氏 ﾎﾞｸらは ｷﾐに命を預ける｡
その代わりに
ｷﾐに課せられた義務がある！
In return, you have an obligation to fulfill.
それは 死なねえことだ！
To not die. Do whatever it takes to live.
何が何でも生き残れ！
No matter how humiliating it may be...
どんなに恥辱にまみれようが➡
目の前で どれだけ
隊士が死んでいこうが➡
No matter how many squad members
die before your eyes, you must live!
ｷﾐは 生きにゃならねえ！
As long as you're here,
(土方)ｷﾐがいるかぎり
真選組は終わらないからだ！
the Shinsengumi is not finished.
We joined the Shinsengumi because we
wanted to be with you...
ﾎﾞｸたちは ｱﾝﾀに惚れて
真選組に入ったからだ！
ﾊﾞｶのくせに難しいこと
考えてんじゃねえよ！
You're an idiot.
Don't think about such difficult things!
You should live the way you want to live.
(土方)ﾃﾒｴは ﾃﾒｴらしく
生きてりゃいいんだ！
(土方)ｵﾚたちは 何者からも
ｿｲﾂを護るだけだ…｡
We just have to protect
you from everyone.
Kondo-san...
近藤さん…｡
ｱﾝﾀは 真選組の魂だ｡
You are the soul of the Shinsengumi.
We are the sword that protects you.
ｵﾚたちは それを護る剣なんだよ｡
Toshi...
(近藤)ﾄｼ…｡
(伊東)一度 折れたｷﾐに
何が護れるというのだ!?
You broke once before.
What can you protect?
Hijikata-kun, it seems we have
to settle things between us.
(伊東)土方君 ｷﾐとはどうあっても
決着をつけねばならぬらしい！
剣なら ここにあるぜ…
よく斬れるやつがよぉ！
I have a sword right here.
One that cuts very well.
♪♪～
Odd Jobs, I heard your rotten sermon!
(土方)万事屋！
聞こえたぜ ﾃﾒｴの腐れ説教！
What is it?
(銀時)なんだい？
(土方)偉そうに➡
Don't talk as if you're so high and mighty.
ﾍﾞﾗﾍﾞﾗ ﾍﾞﾗﾍﾞﾗ語りやがって！
ぬうっ…！
Draw it already!
(銀時)さっさと抜きやがれ｡
(土方)黙りやがれ！
Shut up!
ぬうっ…！
I have one more thing to say to you.
ﾃﾒｴに ひと言 言っておく！
くっ… ううっ…！
(土方)ありがとよぉぉ！
Thank you!!
おいおい… また妖刀に
のまれちまったらしいな｡
Hey, hey, it looks like the demonic sword
devoured him again... Toshi?
ﾄｯｼｰか？ ﾄｯｼｰなのか!?
Is that Toshi?
(土方)ｵﾚは…！
I'm...
[Toshiro Hijikata has fought off the demonic
sword's curse and recovered all by himself.]
[The moment to settle things with his
rival, Kamotaro Ito, has finally come.]
["Important Things Are Hard To See"]
大将の首をとりたくば
このｵﾚを倒してからにしろ！
If you want to kill our boss,
you have to defeat me first.
(土方)何人たりとも
ここは通さねえ｡
I won't let anyone past me. I won't
let anyone disgrace our souls.
何人たりとも
ｵﾚたちの魂は汚させねえ！
ｵﾚは 近藤 勲を護る最後の砦…｡
I am the final fort that
protects Isao Kondo.
真選組を護る最後の剣！
I am the final sword that protects
the Shinsengumi.
真選組副長… 土方 十四郎だぁ！
I am Shinsengumi Vice-Chief...
Toshiro Hijikata!!
自力で妖刀の呪いを ねじ伏せた！
He fought off the demonic
sword's curse by himself.
悪ぃな ｺﾞﾘﾗ｡
残念ながら ﾃﾒｴの依頼は➡
Sorry, Gorilla.
Unfortunately, we can't take your request
no matter how much money you offer us.
なんぼ 金つまれても
受けられねえな…｡
あっちが先客だ｡
He was our client first.
(近藤)ﾌｯ… 仕事は
ここまでじゃなかったのか？
Didn't your job end already?
延長料金は しっかりいただくぜ！
I'm going to be charging overtime pay!
Come on, Ito!
きやがれ 伊東…！
(河上)変わった…
あの男の魂のﾘｽﾞﾑが変わった｡
It changed... The rhythm of that
man's soul has changed.
(河上)幼稚なｱﾆｿﾝから
骨太のﾛｯｸﾝﾛｰﾙでござる｡
It went from a childish anime song
to a sturdy rock-and-roll tune.
いや ぬしもか… 伊東殿｡
I guess the same goes
for you, too, Ito-dono.
(河上)格調高いｸﾗｼｯｸから
凶暴なﾒﾀﾙでござる｡
You've gone from very dignified classical
music to fierce heavy metal.
ﾌｯ… いい曲だ｡
That's a nice song... Play your beautiful
concerto to your heart's content.
思う存分 奏でるがよい｡
美しき協奏曲を…｡
Hijikata!!
土方…！
伊東…！
Ito!!
♪♪～
ﾊﾝﾄﾞﾙが…！
The steering wheel...!
(土方)おい 後ろ… うわっ！
Hey, behind us!!
(土方)うわ～!!
♪♪～
ぐえ！
Kondo-san, move over
to this side already.
(沖田)近藤さん さっさと
こっちへ移ってください｡
(沖田)
…ち～と 働き過ぎちまった｡
I overworked myself a bit... I'm
getting overtime pay for this, right?
残業代 出ますよね？ これ｡
(近藤)総悟！
Sogo?!
ｵﾚが是が非でも
勘定方に掛け合ってやる｡
I'll make sure you negotiate with
the person in charge of our pay.
ｿｲﾂは いいや…｡
That's good. Also, make
sure to take care of him.
ついでに ﾔﾂの始末も
頼みまさぁ｡
ｵﾚは ちょいと
疲れちまったもんで｡
I'm a little tired...
…土方さん 少しでも
遅れをとったら➡
Hijikata-san, if you come out even
a little behind, I'll kill you.
ｵﾚが ｱﾝﾀを殺しますぜ｡
今度 弱み見せたら➡
The next time you show
weakness, I'll take...
次こそは 副長の座
ｵﾚが いただきますよ｡
your position as Vice-Chief.
しかし ﾄｼをおいて
ｵﾚだけ逃げろと言うのか？
But are you saying that I should
just leave Toshi and run away?
ﾓﾀﾓﾀしてんじゃねえよ！
そこで もめんな！
Don't waste your time!!
Don't fight here!!
(土方)つうか ﾃﾒｴら
なんで 当たり前のように➡
Why are you using me like
a bridge as if it's normal?!
人を橋のように 扱ってるんだ！
うわ～！
銀さん！ うわ～！
Gin-san!
うわ… うわ!!
(伊東)土方君｡
Hijikata-kun, you were the only
one who understood me.
ｷﾐは ﾎﾞｸの唯一の理解者だった｡
惜しむらくは ﾎﾞｸの器を知り
恐れ 敵に回ってしまったことか｡
Unfortunately, you knew and feared my
potential and we became enemies.
ｷﾐが もし局長であったならば➡
If you were Chief, I might have
never planned this rebellion.
ﾎﾞｸは 反乱など
企てなかったかもしれないよ｡
ﾌﾌ… あくまで仮説だがね｡
This is just hypothetical, though.
だが ｷﾐも ひとつだけ
ﾎﾞｸを勘違いしている｡
But there's one thing you've
got wrong about me.
ｷﾐが ﾎﾞｸの器を知るように➡
Just as you know my potential,
I also know your potential.
ﾎﾞｸも また
ｷﾐの器を知るということを｡
Toshiro Hijikata, bring it on!!
土方 十四郎 来い！
うお～!!
This is the final showdown!!
最後の決着のときだ～!!
♪♪～
うお～！
ふっ！
♪♪～
(河上)おもしろい音を出すな
お主｡
You have an interesting sound.
でたらめで 気ままで
とらえどころのない音は➡
Your sound is haphazard, willful,
and vague. It's akin to jazz.
ｼﾞｬｽﾞにも 通ずるか｡
But it's undignified. If anything,
it's a drunk's humming.
いや それにしては 品がない｡
例えるなら
酔っ払いの鼻歌でござる｡
ﾃﾒｴ…
高杉のとこにいた野郎だな？
You bastard... You're the guy
who was with Takasugi.
おい 人と話すときは
ﾍｯﾄﾞﾎﾝとりなさい！
Hey, take your headphones off
when you talk to someone.
Gintoki Sakata... No, White Knight...
坂田 銀時… いや 白夜叉｡
なにゆえ お主が
真選組にいるでござるか？
Why are you with the Shinsengumi?
You can hear me, can't you?
ﾃﾒｴ 聞こえてんじゃねえかよ｡
あの男 ﾃﾒｴらの息が
かかった者のようだな｡
That man seems to be
under your influence.
真選組の実権 握らせて
幕府の間者とするつもりか？
Are you planning to spy on the Bakufu
once you take control of the Shinsengumi?
背信行為を
平然とやってのける者を➡
We're not generous enough to be allied
with those who easily betray others.
仲間にするほど
拙者たちは 寛容にござらん｡
また 信義に背く者の元に
人は 集まらぬことも➡
We also know that people will not gather
under a person who has been unfaithful.
拙者たちは 知っている｡
So what of that man?
じゃあ あの男は？
哀れな男でござる｡
He is a pitiful man.
(河上)己が器量 知るときは
もう遅い｡
By the time he realizes his
capacity, it'll be too late.
すべて 砕け散った後だ｡
It'll be after everything
breaks into pieces.
あ!!
眠るがいい 伊東｡
Go to sleep, Ito...
真選組もろとも｡
Along with the Shinsengumi...
((伊東:天才とは
いつも孤独なものだ｡
Geniuses are always alone. I have
no one who understands me.
ﾎﾞｸには 理解者がいない｡
ﾎﾞｸは こんなところで
くすぶっている男ではない｡
I shouldn't remain in a place like this.
誰もそれを理解できない｡
No one understands that. No
one realizes my true worth.
誰も ﾎﾞｸの真の価値に気づかない｡
ならば自らで
己が器を天下に示すしかあるまい｡
In that case,
I just have to demonstrate my potential
to take control of the country.
I will take control of the Shinsengumi.
(伊東)真選組を我がものにする｡
それを地盤にﾎﾞｸは天下に躍進する｡
I will use that as a foundation
to take control of the country.
この伊東 鴨太郎が
生きた証しを天下に…｡
I, Kamotaro Ito, will take control of the
country as proof that I have lived.
人々の心に刻みこんでみせる｡
I will etch that into people's hearts.
(高杉)悪名でもかまわねえと？
You don't mind acquiring
a bad reputation?
In order to achieve what you propose,
そのためなら 恩を受けた
近藤を消すこともいとわねえと？
you have to wipe out Kondo,
whom you are indebted to.
Indebted? Kondo's the one who
should be indebted to me.
恩？ 恩ならば
近藤のほうにあるはずだ｡
あのような無能の男の下に
ﾎﾞｸが 仕えてやったのだ｡
I'm working for an incompetent
man like him.
感謝こそされど
不満を言われる覚えはない｡
He should be thankful. He has no
reason to be dissatisfied with me.
ｳﾌﾌｯ… 伊東よ お前｡
Ito, you're the kind of person
who thinks that everyone aside from
yourself is stupid, aren't you?
自分以外の人間は
みんな ﾊﾞｶだと思ってるｸﾁだろ？
(高杉)だが そのﾊﾞｶな連中に
理解されぬのを不満に思っている｡
But you're unsatisfied that those stupid
people don't understand you.
You want them to understand you.
You want them to acknowledge you.
理解されたいと思っている｡
自分を
見てもらいたいと思っている｡
己が器をしらしめたい？
You want to prove your worth?
It's not that difficult.
そんな大層なもんじゃあるまいよ｡
お前はただ １人だっただけだろ？
You choose to be all by yourself.
(高杉)お前が求めているのは➡
You don't want someone who
understands and accepts you.
自分を認めてくれる
理解者なんかじゃねえ｡
What you really want is...
お前が欲しいものは…))
(雷鳴)
ここは…｡
Where am I?
土方？ そうか ﾎﾞｸは勝った！
Hijikata?
I see... I won! I finally
won against Hijikata...
ﾎﾞｸは遂に土方に勝っ…｡
うわ～っ！
Shinsuke saw through Ito.
晋助は
伊東を看破していたでござる｡
自尊心だけ人一倍強い｡
He is a show-off who has more
pride than anyone else
and doesn't know his own worth.
己の器も知らぬ自己顕示欲の塊｡
It was easy to provoke and use him.
それを刺激し
利用するのは容易なことでござる｡
思惑どおり真選組同士争い
戦力を削ってくれたわ｡
As expected, the Shinsengumi members
fought against each other
and depleted their fighting potential.
You were planning to use him to crush
the Shinsengumi to begin with.
ﾃﾒｴら ﾊﾅから真選組潰すつもりで
ﾔﾂを利用してたってのか｡
You acted as if you were helping
with Ito's rebellion.
伊東の反乱を
手引きし 協力する体を装い➡
仲間割れで 消耗した真選組を
壊滅するつもりだったってのか｡
While you were really planning
to annihilate the Shinsengumi
when it was exhausted after they
fought amongst themselves.
あの男らしい死に方でござろう｡
It's a death that suits that
man, don't you think?
The traitor is wiped out by the traitor.
(河上)裏切り者は
裏切りによって消える｡
や やめてくれ！
S-Stop!
Stop!
《やめてくれ…》
I'm not meant to die in a place like this.
《ﾎﾞｸは
こんなところで 死ぬ男じゃない｡
やめてくれ
ﾎﾞｸはもっとできる男なんだ…｡
Stop. I can do much better...
もっと もっと…》
Much, much better...
Mother!
((伊東:母上！
見てください！
ﾎﾞｸ 学問所の試験で満点を…｡
Take a look! I got a perfect
score on a test at school.
Kamotaro, be quiet. It's bad for
your older brother's health.
鴨太郎 静かになさい｡
兄上の体にさわるでしょ｡
I-I'm very sorry.
も 申し訳ないです｡
《もっと もっとがんばらねば｡
I've got to try much, much harder.
もっと がんばれば
きっと ﾎﾞｸを見てくれる…》
If I try harder, I'm sure she'll notice me.
Yes. That's wonderful, Kamotaro!
(師範)うん みごとだ 鴨太郎｡
お前は我が
学問所始まって以来の神童だ｡
You are the first child prodigy
to come from our school.
Everyone, don't lose to Kamotaro.
皆も鴨太郎に負けるなよ ﾌﾞﾊﾊﾊｯ…｡
調子にのってんじゃねえぞ！
勉強しかできない ﾎﾞﾝﾎﾞﾝがよ！
Don't get cocky.
You're just a rich kid who
only knows how to study!
I've got to try much, much harder.
《伊東:もっと… もっと
がんばらなければ…｡
If I try harder, I'm sure that
everyone will accept me.
もっと がんばれば
きっと みんな 認めてくれる》
One point! Wonderful. You're
really something, Kamo!
(師範)１本！ おみごと｡
たいしたものだ 鴨｡
Such an aptitude for swords at your age.
(師範)この歳にして この剣筋…｡
努力したな｡
You worked hard, didn't you?
(師範)鴨！ 江戸へ行け｡
Kamo, go to Edo.
I'll recommend you to the dojo of the
distinguished Hokuto Itto Style.
私が 名門 北斗一刀流の道場を
推挙してやる｡
こんな田舎では
お前の才気が潰れてしまう｡
Your brilliance will go to waste
out here in the country!
It's possible you might even surpass the
great swordsman Musashi Miyamoto!
お前なら かの剣豪 宮本 武蔵を
超えるのも 不可能ではないぞ｡
Why?
《なんで…》
[Letter of Recommendation]
(伊東の父)まったく…
よりによって 跡取りの鷹久が➡
Honestly. My heir, Takahisa is so sickly.
あれほど 病弱では
我が伊東家は どうなるものやら｡
I wonder what's going to
happen to the Ito family.
Kamotaro grew up so healthily.
鴨太郎は あんなに
元気に育ったというのにな｡
No matter how brilliant our second
son is, it's just a waste of talent.
(伊東の母)次男が
どれだけの才覚を➡
持っていようと 宝の持ち腐れ｡
Takahisa wasn't born to have everything
taken away from him by Kamotaro.
鷹久は 鴨太郎に すべて奪われて
生まれてきたのよ｡
私のお腹の中にいるときに
鴨太郎が鷹久のすべてを➡
I'm sure Kamotaro took everything away
from Takahisa while he was in my womb.
奪っていってしまったに
違いないわ！
I wish he was never born.
あんな子…
生まれてこなければよかったのに｡
Hey! What if Kamotaro hears you?!
What's the matter with you?!
(伊東の父)これ！ 鴨太郎に
聞かれたら どうするんだ!?
どうかしてるぞ！
I feel so sorry for Takahisa.
(伊東の母)だって
私 鷹久が不憫で…｡
When I see Kamotaro carelessly
running about...
何も知らず 無邪気に飛び回る
鴨太郎を見てたら…｡
You must be tired from taking
care of Takahisa.
(伊東の父)鷹久の看病で
疲れてるんだな｡ もう 寝なさい))
Go to bed already.
《なんで… なんで みんな
ﾎﾞｸを見てくれない？
Why? Why doesn't anyone look at me?
こんなに がんばっているのに｡
ﾎﾞｸは 何も悪くないのに｡
I've tried so hard. I'm not at fault.
Look at me. Praise me.
もっと ﾎﾞｸを見てくれ｡
もっと ﾎﾞｸを褒めてくれ》
Don't leave me alone.
《ﾎﾞｸを１人にしないでくれ｡
隣にいてくれ｡ ﾎﾞｸの隣で…｡
Stay by me. By my side.
この手を握ってくれ…》
Hold this hand...
K-Kondo?!
(伊東)こ… 近藤!?
What are you doing?
何をしている!? ｷﾐは 今 何を
しているのか わかっているのか！
Do you know what you're
doing right now?!
I'm the traitor who tried to kill you.
ﾎﾞｸは ｷﾐを殺そうとした裏切り者！
The boss is at fault if there's a revolt.
(近藤)謀反を起こされるのは
大将の罪だ｡
無能な大将につけば兵は命を失う｡
これを斬るは 罪じゃねえ｡
Soldiers will lose their lives if they
stay with an incompetent general.
They're not at fault for killing him.
すまねえ… ｵﾚぁ ｱﾝﾀの上に
立つには足らねえ大将だった｡
Sorry. I'm not a good enough
general to be your superior.
(近藤)もともと ｶﾞﾗじゃねえんだよ
大将なんて ｵﾚぁ｡
I was never suited to be the boss.
You're far more suited to be the boss.
ｱﾝﾀのほうが
よっぽど 大将に向いてらぁ｡
I can't stand by while squad
members are dying.
ｵﾚは 隊士が死んでいくのを
黙って見てるなんざ できねえよ｡
I can't ever use suicide squads.
死兵なんて割り切ることは
できねえ やっぱり｡
Sensei, I'm not a soldier.
先生… ｵﾚぁ 兵隊なんかじゃねえ
ただ 肩 つきあわせて➡
But I wanted you to be by my side as
a friend that I would pour drinks with.
酒をくみ交わす友達として
ｱﾝﾀにいてほしかったんだ｡
There were still so many things I wanted
you to teach me, Sensei...
(近藤)まだまだ ｱﾝﾀにたくさん
いろんなこと➡
教えてほしかったんだ 先生…｡
《ﾎﾞｸが１人なのは
ﾎﾞｸのせいじゃない｡
It's not my fault I'm alone! I'm not at fault!
ﾎﾞｸは 何も悪くない｡
They're incompetent!
They're completely incompetent!
無能だから… ﾔﾂらが無能だから》
We live in different worlds.
I was a chosen individual.
《ﾎﾞｸとﾔﾂらは 住む世界が違う｡
ﾎﾞｸは選ばれた人間なんだ｡
孤独を受け入れられず
孤独であることを人のせいにした｡
I couldn't accept my loneliness and
I blamed my loneliness on others.
I was afraid that people would
reject me, so I rejected them.
人から拒絶されることを恐れ
自分から拒絶した｡
I was afraid I would get hurt, so
I acted as if I liked being alone.
傷つくのを恐れ
孤独が好きな芝居をした｡
I built a wall around my heart.
心に壁ができていく…｡
そのくせ 宙ぶらりんになった
自己顕示欲だけが➡
But my lingering desire for attention
grew stronger by the day.
日増しに大きくなっていく｡
I wanted to be accepted by others.
他者に認められたい｡
認められても まだ満足できない｡
Even when I was accepted,
I wasn't satisfied.
I could do better. I'm not like them.
ﾎﾞｸは もっとできる｡
ﾎﾞｸは お前らと違う！
I'll show them who I am.
思い知らせてやる！
ﾎﾞｸという存在を!!》
You don't want someone who
understands and accepts you.
((お前が求めているのは➡
自分を認めてくれる
理解者なんかじゃねえ))
I had forgotten what I really wanted.
《いつのまにか 忘れていた｡
ﾎﾞｸが 本当に欲しかったもの…｡
It wasn't power, fame, military exploits, talent,
or someone who understood me.
地位や名誉 武功でも才能でも➡
自分を認めてくれる
理解者でもない｡
I just wanted someone to be by my side.
ﾎﾞｸは ただ…
誰か 隣にいてほしかった｡
ただ 誰かに見てほしかった｡
I just wanted someone to see me.
I just didn't want to be alone anymore.
ただ １人がｲﾔだった》
《ただ…》
I just wanted...
(近藤)ぬお～っ！ 先生！
Sensei!
(神楽)うんごぉ…！
《伊東:正面から
受け止めてくれる仲間…》
Friends who would accept
me for who I was.
(ｶﾞﾝﾅｰ)おい… あれ 見ろ！
Hey, look over there!
何してやがる！
What are you doing?!
(土方)さっさと逃げやがれ！
Hurry up and run away!
《正面から ﾎﾞｸを見…》
Someone who would
look directly at me...
((２人:いずれ殺してやるよ))
Someday, I'll kill you.
うおぉ！
《ぶつかってくるﾔﾂ｡
ただ… 仲間が欲しかった｡
And take me head on.
I just...
Wanted friends.
ﾎﾞｸの欲しかったものは➡
The thing I wanted...
もう… とっくの昔に
ここにあった》
Was something...
I already had.
土方君｡ ｷﾐに言いたいことが
ひとつ あったんだ｡
Hijikata-kun, I have something
I want to say to you.
奇遇だな ｵﾚもだ｡
What a coincidence. Me, too.
ﾎﾞｸは ｷﾐが嫌いだ｡
(土方)ﾎﾞｸは お前が嫌いだ｡
I hate you.
(土方/伊東)
いずれ 殺してやる｡ だから…➡
Someday, I'll kill you. So...
こんなところで死ぬな！
Don't die here.
《ﾎﾞｸの欲しかった絆は もう…➡
The bond I wanted so much...
ずっと前から つながっていた》
Was right here all along.
うおおおお！
うおおおおお！
太刀筋が… ﾘｽﾞﾑが見えない！
I can't see your swings or your rhythm!
どけ この野郎！
Out of the way, damn it!!
ﾃﾒｴらは➡
Don't you understand that...
どけっつってんのが
わかんねえのか!!
I'm telling you to get out of my way?!
ﾃﾒｴらみてぇな ﾀｺ助に
構ってる暇は ねえんだよ！
I don't have the time
to deal with...
idiots like you!
弦!?
Strings?!
無理は せぬがいい｡
手足が ちぎれるでござるぞ｡
You shouldn't push yourself.
Your arms and legs will rip off.
今さら 助けに
行ったところで もう遅い｡
Even if you go to help
them now, it's too late.
(河上)主は まだ
仲間が生きていると？
Do you think your friends are still alive?
たとえ あの爆発の中を
生き残っていようと➡
Even if they survived that explosion...
策は 幾重にも
弄してあるでござる｡
We've taken many measures.
真選組は消える｡
The Shinsengumi will disappear.
くっ… うっ…｡
手足がちぎれると
言ったはずでござる！
I told you that your arms
and legs will rip off.
ﾌｯ… 誰が あんな連中
助けに行きてぇかよ｡
Who'd want to go and save their sorry asses?
I can't stop. My body won't listen to me.
止まらねえんだよ｡
体が 言うことを聞かねえ｡
勝手に 前に引き寄せられる…｡
It's being pulled forward.
Strings are pulling me from
the front and the back.
前からも 後ろからも
糸が絡まって➡
引っ張ってきやがる｡
うっとうしくて しかたねえ！
It annoys me to no end...
《鉄の強度を誇る弦が…!?》
These strings are as strong
as steel, but still...
You can have an arm and a leg or two...
手足の１本や２本 くれてやらぁ｡
んだが 肉は切れても
この糸… 腐れ縁！
Even if these strings can cut flesh...
I'd like to see them
try to sever
切れるもんなら 切ってみやがれ!!
an obnoxious bond!
♪♪～
伏せろ！
Get down!
うお～っ!!
♪♪～
ｺﾞﾎｯ…｡
先生!!
伊東…!?
Ito!
Sensei!
ｺﾞﾎｯ…｡
伊東!!
Ito!
うわっ！
うおらぁ!!
[To be continued]
[Preview]
Hey, young man, clean out
your ears and listen up!
I've never once fought for the
sake of this cheap country.
I couldn't care less if the
country or samurai fell.
["It's All About the Beat and Timing"]
[What did he find when he tugged
on the invisible strings?!]
[The Shinsengumi Crisis Arc
ends in the next episode!!]